Hello everyone and welcome back
to another lesson at English Pod.
My name is Marko and
my name is Catherine and
in the spirit of Halloween we
have a Halloween lesson for you.
Happy Halloween!
It's Halloween.
It's Halloween and
this is an elementary
level lesson so we're talking about
some basic but important things today.
Exactly so we're not
going to preview anything
because the dialogue
is pretty simple.
So why don't we listen to it for
the first time and we'll be right back.
Trick-or-tree.
Tom, aren't you little too
old to be trick-or-treating?
What are you talking about?
Where's your Halloween spirit?
Didn't you ever dress
up in a costume and
go around the neighborhood
trick-or-treating with your friends?
Of course I did but when I was
10, trick-or-treating is for kids.
Plus I'm sure people
think you're a kid-nap or
something running
around with kids at night.
Whatever.
I'm going next door.
I heard Mrs.
Robinson is giving out big bags of M&Ms.
Alright we're back so trick-or-treating.
Ding-dong.
Trick-or-treat.
Alright so we're going
to explain what the
trick-or-treating is
just in a little bit but
before we get into
it why don't we take a
look at four important
words in language take away.
Language take away.
Well the first one
that Marco is very
important because it's
the name of this special
holiday that isn't
celebrated everywhere.
It's only celebrated in some places
and Americans I think love it above all us.
Right, yeah.
Halloween.
Now it just actually comes
from all hollows Eve, right?
That's right.
It's the night of the spirits of the dead.
Alright exactly.
So the day of the
dead and as Catherine
mentions it's celebrated
in different ways in
different countries
but I think probably the
United States is one
of the few that where
people dress up and go
trick-or-treating and that's right.
And Halloween is the last day of October so
October 31st and it's a really fun holiday
where mostly children dress up in
costumes and they ask for candy.
Alright so to dress up
means to get in the costume.
Right well you could say dress up to mean a
couple of different things but in this case
you dress up in a costume so that means you
change your clothes so that you're wearing
a costume which is maybe a witches
costume or a vampire or something scary.
So you would say he
dressed up as a vampire.
He dressed up as a vampire or
they got dressed up for the wedding.
Okay very good.
So dress up and then we
have the word "kidnapper".
So the friend is afraid
that his friend will look
like a kidnapper who goes out
trick-or-treating with the kids.
And so a kid napper comes
from the word to take or to grab.
So kid grabber and that
means that you're going
to take children from
the streets and steal them.
Right but you can kidnap an
adult right so it's not only for kids.
That's right.
It's for any kind of
person who you take
without them wanting
you to so against their will.
Okay kid napper.
And finally we have M&M's.
What are M&M's?
Not to sing it right?
No M&M is spelled differently the singer.
This is a delicious chocolate treat.
It's a candy and it comes
in big brown bags and if
you want them with peanuts
they come in a yellow bag.
And you know your M&M's.
Oh man I could tell you all the colors.
But M&M's are really delicious
and it's actually a brand M&M.
It's a brand.
Right so many people
will probably know it but
just in case they're called
M&M's very good candy.
Alright so these words
were relatively easy and
simple so why don't we
listen to our dialogue again.
Let's slow it down
just a little bit and
we'll be right back to take
a look at fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
Alright we're back.
On fluency builder we
promised that we were
going to look at this word
trick-or-treating so let's look at it now.
Trick-or-treat.
It's a verb right?
To trick-or-treat and it comes
from the words that we say
when we're children to the
person who's door we knock on.
So for example I say
and then I open the door.
I say trick-or-treat.
Okay so what are you supposed to do in
this when somebody says trick-or-treat?
Well I'm a child I'm
holding my bag and you're
supposed to say happy
Halloween and give me some candy.
Okay.
Alright so trick-or-treat means
you could either trick someone.
You could play a
trick on them like scare
them or put some toilet paper on
their house or you can give them a treat.
Or accept a treat and
so the idea is if you don't
give me a treat I will do
something bad to you.
I see but this doesn't
really happen right
like when kids go to
people's houses they say
trick-or-treat and then
they get candy automatically.
Almost automatically
yeah sometimes people
avoid the holiday and
they close their doors
and lock them and they
don't answer the door.
And that's when someone
maybe throws an egg at the
house or does the toilet
paper on their treats.
Yeah.
So trick-or-treat is
what we say but it's
also something we can do
so we can go trick or treating.
Go trick-or-treat.
Okay very good
trick-or-treat and now we have
another phrase here
that's a little bit complicated
but when the friend
answered the door he said
aren't you a little too
old to be trick-or-treating?
Alright I like this phrase
because it's sarcastic
the person is not asking a real question
he's saying listen you are too old to be
trick-or-treating and
so in this case aren't
you is a way to introduce
something that we know is true
that we think is true it's
kind of rude and sarcastic.
So if I say aren't you
supposed to be at work?
Oh right so it's in
that form you're not
really asking a question you're
more demanding an explanation.
Right it's a suggestion it's like you're
probably supposed to be at work right now.
So Marco aren't you supposed
to be at school right now?
So do we always but
we always use it in that
sense right aren't you
and then aren't you?
Aren't you a little old
for that kind of an outfit?
Alright so aren't you all right very good
so those are the two phrases for fluency
builder today let's
listen quickly to our
dialogue one more time
and we'll be right back.
Trick-or-treat Tom aren't you a
little too old to be trick-or-treating?
What are you talking about?
Where's your Halloween spirit?
Didn't you ever dress
up in a costume and
go around the neighborhood
trick-or-treating with your friends?
Of course I did
but when I was ten
trick-or-treating is for
kids plus I'm sure people
think you're a kid nap
or something running
around with kids at night
whatever I'm going next door.
I heard Mrs.
Robinson is giving out big bags of M&Ms.
Alright so Marco have
you ever trick-or-treated?
I did I did I used to
go trick-or-treating
when I was little and it
was actually really fun.
We used to have competitions
about who had the most candy.
I've heard about this.
Right because you don't
necessarily bring a bag
you bring a pillowcase and you
fill your pillowcase with candy.
Now the interesting
thing is that sometimes
you wouldn't necessarily
only get candy from people.
Right sometimes you got weird things
like pennies or toothbrushes or apples.
So you would go to
someone's house and they
would give you a nap
while you'd be like okay.
But there is always an
old lady who lived near
well she lives in the
neighborhood and every
neighborhood had one
you know all my friends
had a lady they would
go to and she gave
the full size candy bars.
Right because
normally stores sell small
candy bars for the
Halloween holiday because
they're smaller they're cheaper that's
easier to give them to many people.
But there's always one
person who has the big
full size candy bars and
everyone goes to her.
Right exactly.
And actually it's
amazing how Halloween is
such an important event in the States because
everyone dresses up, everyone puts out
decorations or pumpkins
outside of their homes.
They have pumpkin
carving contests which
are really cool how
they carve out pumpkins.
They make faces in the
pumpkins and then we can
put a candle inside or
light it up it's really fun.
So that's called a jack-o'-lantern right?
That's right.
Why is it called a jack-o'-lantern?
Do you know?
I have no idea maybe
it's like a jack like a person
looks like a person's
maybe a jack-o'-lantern.
A lantern is a light
you know it's like a
light with a candle in
it so yeah it's actually
very it's a very fun holiday it's it's
really interesting and it's kind of strange
when people really
oppose it because they
say that it's you know
it has to do with the
devil or it has to do
it's a pagan ritual and
things like this but you
know it's just good fun.
It's silly everyone likes
to dress up in a costume.
Well it was the weirdest
costume that you've
dressed up as as an
adult or a child because
I know you've dressed
up as an adult as well.
I dress up every year I
was maybe long-stalking
last year well as a
child one year I dressed
up as an injured soldier
because like my dad
was in the military so
we always had fatigues
around the house and
so I used his fatigues and
I like put blood on my
face and I had crutches
and people thought
that I really had a broken
leg so they used to give me double they
gave me that that year they gave me double
the candy because I
thought oh here's a poor
growing crutches and
trigger treaty and my
my my costume was
an injured soldier so they
didn't understand
that it's really funny.
Nice.
Well we want to hear
about you guys if you go
trick or treating or if you
dress up for Halloween
I know that many places
around the world have
parties or festivities for
Halloween and people
dress up so come to
our website englishpot.
com we'll see you guys there
and we'll see you guys next time.
Happy Halloween.